Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [INFORMATION

Notice Period: 1 Month

SCIENCE]



Database Developer with 7 years in the Finance & Retail domain. Experience in complete software development lifecycle using Scrum and Agile. Experience in project planning, functional and design specification, coding, implementation and maintenance.



Current Designation: Apprentice Leader

Current Company: Mu Sigma

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Noida, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Gurgaon Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Developer, Application Development, Teradata SQL, ETL, SQL, PLSQL, Data Warehousing, Technical

Team Leader, SQL Server, Cursor, Performance Tuning, Agile, Scrum Master, Delivery Management, Data

Engineer, Hadoop, Spark

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 14-Jan-21 Last Modified: 14-Jan-21

## **Summary**

Database Developer with 7 years in the Finance & Retail domain. Experience in complete software development lifecycle using Scrum and Agile. Experience in project planning, system design, functional and design specification, coding, implementation and maintenance. Extensive knowledge and Experience in dealing with Relational Database Management Systems including Normalization, Stored Procedures, Constraints, Querying, Joins, Keys, Indexes, Triggers, and Cursors.

# **Work Experience**

**Mu Sigma** as Apprentice Leader Jun 2018 to Till Date

Working as a Senior Database Application Developer in the account. Responsible for providing solutions to all data related needs to support existing & new applications. Managing a team of developers & QA and delegated tasks. Experience of working as scrum master in agile environment. Supported multiple concurrent projects enabling technical resolution.

**Capgemini** as Senior Analyst -IT Software - Application Programming Mar 2016 to May 2017

Worked as Database Application developer Responsible for developing and implementing database system based on customer requirement. Responsible to optimize the database application.

Creating proof of concept for business analyst. Working on troubleshoot and adhoc request.

Oracle Financial Services Software as Associate Consultant

Oct 2013 to Mar 2016

Worked as Database Application developer. Responsible for developing and implementing database system based on customer requirement.

Creation of complex stored procedures and SQL query to support application development. Identify issue related to database performance and provide solution to customer.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (INFORMATION SCIENCE) from Bangalore Institute Of Technology (BIT) in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Oracle Database SQL certification in 2015

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SQL Developer , PL SQL Developer			6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
GIT			1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JIRA			1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
WINDOWS			6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
TERADATA SQL			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Oracle SQL			3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
CONFLUENCE			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SQL Server			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Python			0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
DATA WAREHOUSING			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

# **Languages Known**

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time